<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>ivy sly ∙ blog</title><link href="https://ivysly.com/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ivysly.com/blog/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://ivysly.com/blog/</id><updated>2020-07-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Observations on the Discord-Twitter Dynamic</title><link href="https://ivysly.com/blog/hyperforum-macrochannel.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Ivy Sly</name></author><id>tag:ivysly.com,2020-07-14:/blog/hyperforum-macrochannel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My thoughts on the evolution of what I call the hyperforum and the macrochannel. Some things I've noticed about the separation of online culture into two new major forms (reversed from their original purposes) and how they interact with each other. Why teenagers are being ludicrously racist. An unreadable diagram.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Something curious to me is the behavior of private gatherings in online chat 
rooms (before, Skype; further still, IRC; now, Discord) and their roles as 
highly efficient avenues for developing microculture, rapid discourse, and
sharing discovery. In the early-mid 10's I was a member 
of some extremely active groups of musicians
on Skype, and some of them have gone on to see considerable success in their 
niche&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="#fn1" id="ref1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. 
Even when you are allotted just one room, a consensus is made quickly on the 
etiquette, direction, and, often, the path to innovation in the group's subject 
interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discord harmonizes with this quality. Users are given the opportunity to
now expand their groups into multiple rooms, explicitly specifying what you are 
allowed to talk about and where, with varying levels of moderator 
abities for rule enforcement and wanton power play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Shortcut To Esotericism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the hyperforum. &lt;strong&gt;Frozen in time, a substantially large Discord server is 
entirely indistinguishable from the message boards one might have seen 
spattering the Web in the naughts and early 10's&lt;/strong&gt;—except, this time, 
communication is &lt;em&gt;instant&lt;/em&gt;, and you don't have to spend the cash, 
time, or brain power setting it up 
yourself. 
In scope and accessibility, nothing like this has ever been done before, nor has
it even come close. The process behind hosting a place of 
discussion&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="#fn2" id="ref2"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; 
quickly transformed from an 
ordeal usually reserved for sorcerers with knowledge of arcane arts like "php" 
or "DNS" to something any computer-literate putz can do for free. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ding! You've received an invite to a private Discord server.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immediately, you enter a new, 
instantly eternal universe of unintelligible discourse and 
alien social norms. Every server you're in has a hackjob Python robot arbiter 
scanning your outward messages and updating some obscure variable if your 
post matches one of its many regex 
patterns&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="#fn3" id="ref3"&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it's obviously not news that any exclusive group or niche will develop 
a unique culture. But consider the 
userbase&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="#fn4" id="ref4"&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; we are talking about here.
Internet microcultures are blossoming into troves of art and knowledge at an
unprecedented frequency. Make no mistake, I think this is beautiful and profound, 
and the effects on meatspace outer-culture are certainly going to be 
unpredictable (this is already proving to be the case).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insular web communities full of overly-online weirdos and teenagers 
aren't wholly without fault, however. I don't want to rehash
what a thousand people have said about why echo chambers are bad,
but I do want to touch on a few things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I Can't Understand What The Kids Are Saying But I Think It's Racist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the sphere of quickly evolving discussion, one must reduce their environment to
its symbols; it's simply impossible to keep track of the holistic human
being behind every user avatar on every server you participate in. Vice versa, 
better your own identity be reduced to the symbols you choose, so
that you can adequately maintain the pace without muddying up the discourse 
(in fact, it is impossible not to do this).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While talking to a &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/wifihermit"&gt;friend&lt;/a&gt; about this, he made a good point to me. Consider the 
"starter pack" meme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="An example of the starter pack meme posted to Twitter." src="https://ivysly.com/blog/images/starterpack.png"&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;An example of the starter pack meme posted to Twitter.&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intent here is to categorize people into
"types"&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="#fn5" id="ref5"&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Everything gets much easier
when the world becomes simple. You begin to think this way of yourself. What
starterpack describes me? What symbols do people imagine when they read my
messages? When they see my avatar? What container contains me? Is it more than
one?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This framework of pathological categorization is shared by identity politics, 
neoliberalism, capitalism, fascism, etc.—that is to say, ideologies that are bent on 
"efficiency" despite their emphasis of form over function. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, of course we are seeing a radical divide towards the extremes. Reducing the 
world to its signifiers leaves no room for anything else. And it's obvious why
even the most heinous poasters don't pay their actions any mind: people in webforums 
are no longer material human beings. We are primarily &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; engaging with the 
material. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what difference does it make when you're only racist online?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, for one, most people can't help but to be their race &lt;em&gt;all of the time&lt;/em&gt;. 
Also, now that we've established an environment of symbolism and
identity politics, what you do or say online is indistinguishable from what
you do in material space. You aren't only racist online, you're only racist
&lt;em&gt;sometimes&lt;/em&gt;. There is no difference; the medium is no longer the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there are many names for the vehement response to online fascism; 
"Cancel culture", "censorship", "SJW" something or other. But ultimately
how the Left responds to this is barely praxis at all. &lt;strong&gt;It does not matter
if you are "cancelled". It means nothing.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Macrochannel: The Long Way Around to The Thing You Were Already Doing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I get too far ahead of myself, let's talk about the underlying 
canvas of internet discourse, so that we can see how these large-scale
interactions (e.g. being "cancelled") are taking place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter is what I call a "macrochannel"—in other words, Twitter is more like
an IRC channel than Discord is, but with a few dozen million active users and only 
a pittance of options to filter them out. The difference between the apparent use 
cases is surprising; Discord is home to sprawling community, but Twitter's 
deliberate lack of structure seems to at best lead to small niche in-groups, and they 
are all under constant surveillance by those adjacent to 
them&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="#fn6" id="ref6"&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the more public-facing, "open" center of discussion seems like the 
least conducive to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's important, also, to understand that Twitter has an understated, tertiary, 
emergent function. Twitter itself is an efficient 
backdoor to many of the closed communities on
hyperforums. If a link is not 
already in someone's bio, it only takes a 
bit of parasocial trust-building before you are 
invited to the back stage workshop 
responsible for a cult of personality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This binary is largely what separates modern internet discourse from its past forms. 
Despite their enormous popularity in the same crowds, a state of tension exists 
between the communities on Discord and those on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Invisible Hand of Meta-Slacktivism and Zoomer PR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is happening when two or more of these Twitter accounts clash
publicly, with seemingly no setup or substantial history between the two?
Of course people have their private affairs, and sometimes they go public, 
but I posit there tends to be a manufactured element to this—not that either 
party are being ingenuine, nor that bad blood is farcical, nor that allegations 
are untrue, but that often the goal of and process behind this is more than just 
realizing one's own desire for justice or conflict. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your identity is not just showcased by these interactions, 
it is &lt;em&gt;defined&lt;/em&gt; by them. Your vicious beef with @cum_chungus69
encompasses more than just your distaste for them; it is the basis for your
claim to humanity inside the chatroom (take a look at the accounts people call 
"bots". Usually, they aren't). After all, isn't there a reason we are making
anything public? Isn't the idea to delegate influence within the platform you
are on? It is not like we are in town square, and can punish offenders directly,
or vote on some legislature, or &lt;em&gt;win anything&lt;/em&gt;. We can't &lt;em&gt;do a communism&lt;/em&gt; on 
Twitter—categorically this does not even make sense. Ultimately, 
no matter how right your cause is, the best thing you can do is put an asterisk 
on someone's entry in the archive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Well, fuck it, that's what we're gonna have to do then, right?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discord is the perfect engine for this. It is a tool molded for 
the microculture war, something a niche can use to determine where to draw the border
between us and them, something they can use to delimit what dirt is and subsequently 
dig it up. With tools like this, we've reached a new capacity for the simulation 
of activism on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand that I am not 
even referring to something like the 
"leftists vs fascists"
conflict, because this is occuring on much smaller levels too: "leftists vs 
different leftists", "philosophy dweebs vs teenagers", "anime pfp's vs normal
people", "kpop stans vs..."&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="#fn7" id="ref7"&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be helpful to understand it like this: the Twitter matrix 
is simultaneously the history book written by the cumulative minds of hyperforums (on 
Discord) and the battleground they are fighting on; it is the history book in that 
it is pseudo-nonfiction (all Twitter personalities and interactions between them 
are inherently editorialized), and the battleground because it is 
nonetheless a place of genuine ideological conflict—it is &lt;em&gt;hyperreal&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="#ref1" id="fn1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; 
Unfortunately, my niche was and remains "whatever I'm feeling
like doing at the time". I'll let you know when it works out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="#ref2" id="fn2"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; 
While we are making up words, how about "cyber-symposium"?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="#ref3" id="fn3"&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; 
Of course, it may alert you to this, or it may not—or perhaps
instead you may simply query the robot and it will harmlessly spit out a
naked or half-naked anime woman back at you, and for one small moment you are
invited to enjoy the artwork before it is consumed by the endless swathes of
newer posts; infinitely ninja'd. This impermance is illusory, though. That 
catgirl will be there for as long as the server exists, and Discord itself 
invites you to index it for older messages in a way  much more akin 
to a bulletin board than an IRC channel. 
At what point are we still calling Discord a chatroom?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="#ref4" id="fn4"&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; 
I do not mean to alarm you, but twenty-somethings masquerading as 
Japanese cartoon girls are exposing your teenager to Deleuze &lt;em&gt;this very second&lt;/em&gt;. 
And there's nothing you can do about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="#ref5" id="fn5"&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; 
Related: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%22new%20type%20of%20guy%22&amp;amp;src=typed_query&amp;amp;f=live"&gt;this meme&lt;/a&gt; which is very 
popular at the time of writing. Furthermore, at this point, 
suffice it to say that Jean Baudrillard's writings on 
simulation and symbols are relevant to the whole article.
I suggest afterwards you skim the book, &lt;em&gt;Simulacra and Simulation&lt;/em&gt;, which you can 
find pdf's of on Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="#ref6" id="fn6"&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; 
&lt;a href="https://www.opendemocracy.net/en/opendemocracyuk/exiting-vampire-castle/"&gt;I am not the first person to point this out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="#ref7" id="fn7"&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
...I don't need to tell you how unintelligible this gets.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry></feed>